Lincolnshire, Ill. Washburn Congregational Church records, 1895-2007.
Congregational Library & Archives
Lincolnshire, Ill. Washburn Congregational Church records, 1895-2007.
RG5569
Congregational Library & Archives
1.21 Cubic Feet
The Washburn Congregational Church was gathered in the summer of 1895 in Half Day, Illinois. Due to the changes of town borders, the church existed in Half Day, Prairie View, and then finally Lincolnshire. The church closed around 2011. This collection contains both administrative and membership records and includes meeting minutes, vital records, auxiliary club records, and scrapbooks.
Washburn Congregational Church (Lincolnshire, Ill.)
Washburn Congregational Church (Half Day, Ill.)
Washburn Congregational Church (Prairie View, Ill.)
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
Materials were donated to the Congregational Library & Archives by the Illinois Conference of the United Church of Christ in December 2024; accession number 2024-46. The 1895 correspondence and the 1954 annual report were transferred to the archive from the library, January 2026.
Historical Note
The Washburn Congregational Church was gathered in the summer of 1895 in Half Day, Illinois. It was named after Seth Washburn, who had been appointed as the first postmaster in Lake County in 1836 and whose land the church was built on after his descendants donated it. Though the church building never changed after its initial construction, the town borders surrounding it fluctuated between Half Day, Prairie View, and finally Lincolnshire. The church joined the United Church of Christ. The church closed around 2011, the last year it appears in the UCC yearbook.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains both administrative and membership records for the Washburn Congregational Church in Lincolnshire, Illinois. The records include meeting minutes and other types of church records, cradle rolls, membership records, auxiliary club records, women's group records, and scrapbooks.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into chronological order by start date.
Bibliography
Gale, Neil. "Lost Towns of Illinois – Half Day, Illinois." Digital Research Library of Illinois History Journal (blog), published December 25, 2016. Accessed January 13, 2026. https://drloihjournal.blogspot.com/2016/12/lost-towns-of-illinois-half-day-illinois.html
Baptismal records.; Church membership.; Church records and registers.; Marriage records.; Necrologies.; Scrapbooks.; Women -- Societies and clubs.; Half Day (Ill.) -- Church history.; Lincolnshire (Ill.) -- Church history.; Prairie View (Ill.) -- Church history.; Washburn Congregational Church (Half Day, Ill.); Washburn Congregational Church (Lincolnshire, Ill.); Washburn Congregational Church (Prairie View, Ill.)
- Funerals, 1877 1954; 1877-1954 (Box 1, Volume 1)
- Correspondence, 1895 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Church records, 1895 1932; 1895-1932 (Box 1, Volume 2)
- Baptisms and marriages, 1895 1954; 1895-1954 (Box 1, Volume 3)
- Scrapbook, 1895 1987; 1895-1987 (Box 3, Volume 2)
- Cradle roll, 1910 1945; 1910-1945 (Box 1, Volume 4)
- Vernon social club records, 1915 1917; 1915-1917 (Box 1, Volume 5)
- Church membership, 1917 1955; 1917-1955 (Box 2, Volume 1)
- Vernon social club records, 1918 1920; 1918-1920 (Box 1, Volume 6)
- Church membership, 1933 1952; 1933-1952 (Box 1, Volume 7)
- Cradle roll, 1941 1947; 1941-1947 (Box 1, Volume 8)
- Church records, 1943 1951; 1943-1951 (Box 1, Volume 9)
- Cradle roll, 1945 1951; 1945-1951 (Box 1, Volume 10)
- Church records, 1951 1955; 1951-1955 (Box 2, Volume 2)
- Annual report, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Constitutions, 1954 1970; 1954, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Women's fellowship records, 1957 1961; 1957-1961 (Box 2, Volume 3)
- Church records, 1960 1986; 1960-1986 (Box 2, Volume 4)
- Women's fellowship records, 1962 1970; 1962-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1922 building dedication service program photocopy, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Scrapbook, 1988 2007; 1988-2007 (Box 3, Volume 1)